Brian E. Mallen

UX/UI Designer







Summary

Former small business executive turned designer. I focused on crafting better user experiences through problem-solving and detailed analysis. I can take an idea from concept to full product using my full array of design skills. I'm a nerd for color theory and accessibility.

Experience

UX/UI Designer

Jahnel Group

12/2020 - Present

As part of this software development company, I work on a variety of projects and teams. Some projects I work as part of the discovery team at the ground level. We work with key stakeholders to define the product, the brand, and it's path forward. Following discovery we continue through to design and development. Other projects I come in as a supplemental resource, acting as a full member of the product team.

UX/UI Designer

LovetoKnow Media

10/2020 - 05/2021

I was the sole designer working on the GolfLink Brand of LoveToKnow Media. It was a small team consisting of the general manager, product manager, QA and Engineering teams, and significant input from the CEO. Working with this team, we identified and prioritized design opportunities. My biggest accomplishment was refining the brand's digital design system and component library.

UI/UX Designer

PlateRate

06/2020 - 12/2020

I worked as a part of the design team using Scrum framework to help with the product's redesign. I created and implemented the design system, as well as contributed to the visual design. My responsibilities also included user research, competitive analysis, and user testing.

Product Design Apprentice

Bloc by Thinkful

09/2019 - 04/2020

Bloc is where I started my transition into full-time design work. I learned industry best practices and design process standards. The focus during my time at bloc was UX Research, Visual Design, and Front-End Development. I completed over 500 hours of project-based work under the mentorship of senior design professionals.

Assistant Director

Eagle's Landing Day Camp & Events

09/2012 - 08/2019

In my pre-design days, I ran a day camp and event facility. My responsibilities included staff training, facility operations, program development, and much more. My design responsibilities included website redesigns, graphics, and display material. This is where I honed my leadership skills and problem-solving abilities.

Skills

Design

User Research, Design & Content Strategy, User Interface, Web & Mobile Design, User Stories & Flows, Prototyping, User Testing, Wireframing, Mockups, Branding

Software

Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, XD, Sketch, Invision, Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Interpersonal

Leadership, Teamwork, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Communication, Conflict Resolution, Autonomy

Education

Bloc

Product Design Apprenticeship 2020

Rutgers University

Bachelors of Sociology 2012